Jack: Let's look at different
technologies that use code to run.
The Internet of Things or IoT are
becoming commonplace in our lives today
and the range of items that use coding
to run are expanding all the time.
IoT technologies that use code to work,
include coffee machines, light bulbs,
showers, cooking appliances and baby
monitoring equipment to name but a few.
Coding can help programme our appliances
to know where we are, what time we get
up, how healthy we are, what we like
to eat and even how we like it cooked.
Leah: Smart heating and lighting in our
smart homes can help to keep us cool
or warm us up, making sure our homes
are ready for us when we return’ with
the lights turned on for us and even
in a range of colours of our choosing.
Wearable tech can monitor our fitness and
health telling us when to move and when to
sit down, helping us to reach our fitness
goals and making sure we stay healthy
in the process and sleep well at night.
Jack: When we shower after a run or when
we wake up in the morning the temperature
of the shower and time we shower for,
can be monitored for economic purposes.
Tech savvy parents can monitor their
babies to alleviate their anxieties using
monitoring equipment, smart clothing,
temperature control and monitoring
and watch over them with smart toys.
Leah: We use coded programmed systems
to help us purchase goods and have
them delivered or pick them up.
We use it to help us travel
nationally on public transport
and for international travel.
Electric cars can tell us where
to go, how to get there and can
even take the controls themselves
and drive us there at times.
Jack: We have now moved from coding
and programming being involved in
just computer-based systems which
carry the data on us and our lives.
Mobile digital devices and smart
phones and IoT gives us the
opportunity through coding and
programming to be always connected
to all things social, work and play.
Leah: It's amazing to think of
all the common objects and things
we use today that are programmed
to run code, and how it affects
our life and the way we live it.
It also means that there is a vast world
of coding and programming needs out
there, and jobs for those who want to get
involved in the industry and see in the
next wave of advancements and additions.